If you've got a taste for terror… take Carrie to the prom.
Carrie is a horror, thriller film directed by Brian De Palma.
Withdrawn and sensitive teenager Carrie White faces bullying from
classmates and abuse from her fanatically pious mother.
When she begins to suspect that she has supernatural
powers, things take a dark and violent turn.
Carrie, played by Sissy Spacek.
Margaret White, played by Piper Laurie.
Sue Snell, played by Amy Irving.
Tommy Ross, played by William Katt.
Billy Nolan, played by John Travolta.
Chris Hargenson, played by Nancy Allen.
Carrie is a 1976 American supernatural horror film directed by Brian
De Palma from a screenplay written by Lawrence D.
Cohen, adapted from Stephen King's 1974 semi-epistolary novel Carrie.
The film stars Sissy Spacek as Carrie White, a shy teenage girl
who is constantly mocked and bullied at her school.
She later develops the power of telekinesis and uses it
to wreak vengeance on her tormentors.
The film also features Piper Laurie, Amy Irving, Nancy Allen, William Katt, P.
Soles, Betty Buckley, and John Travolta in supporting roles.
It is the first film in the Carrie franchise.
The film was based on King's first published novel.
De Palma was intrigued by the story and pushed for the studio's permission to
direct while Spacek was encouraged by her husband to audition.
It is the first of more than 100 film, television and theater productions
adapted from, or based on, the published works of King.
Theatrically released on November 3, 1976, by United Artists, Carrie became critically and
commercially successful, grossing over $33.8 million against its $1.8 million budget.
It received two nominations at the 49th Academy Awards: Best Actress
(for Spacek) and Best Supporting Actress (for Laurie).
Critics and audience members alike widely cite it as the best adaptation of the novel among the numerous films and
television shows based on the character, as well as one of the best films based on King's publications.
The film has significantly influenced popular culture, with several
publications regarding it as one of the greatest horror films ever made.
In 2008, Carrie was ranked 86th on Empire's list of
The 500 Greatest Movies of All Time.
It was ranked 15th on Entertainment Weekly's list of the 50 Best High School Movies, and
46th on the American Film Institute list AFI's 100 Years...100 Thrills.
The film's prom scene has had a major influence on popular culture and was ranked
eighth on Bravo's 2004 program The 100 Scariest Movie Moments.
In 2022, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of high school, child abuse,
based on novel or book, isolation, cemetery.
The tone is dark and intense.